<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Joshua Pham's blog - posts</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/posts.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2016-09-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Thinking outside the Board: Redesigning Pinterest's organization model</title><link href="/thinking-outside-the-board-redesigning-pinterests-organization-model.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-19T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-09-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Joshua Pham</name></author><id>tag:None,2016-09-19:/thinking-outside-the-board-redesigning-pinterests-organization-model.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Pinterest goes by the name of a “visual discovery tool,” and it is good at finding content for users. It’s good at information retrieval, but perhaps it’s a signifier of underutilized potential that, seemingly by casual extension of this functionality, Pinterest serves as a mood-boarding tool. What if …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Pinterest goes by the name of a “visual discovery tool,” and it is good at finding content for users. It’s good at information retrieval, but perhaps it’s a signifier of underutilized potential that, seemingly by casual extension of this functionality, Pinterest serves as a mood-boarding tool. What if it allowed users to do more than just hoard content en masse into Boards? I had questions about what mood-boarding could be through Pinterest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Principles of Interaction Design class assigned several projects involving user studies, and I took this liberty to address this curiosity of mine. I surveyed some fellow Pinterest users, then dreamt up a paper prototype. What follows is a summary of my study and design, as well as some reflection upon writing this up a few months after the class ended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/@joshuapham/pinterest-boards-have-a-size-problem-ac878f17e19b#.tozlrgbvx"&gt;Read more in the Medium post!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is abridged from a design concept that I wrote about for Principles of Interaction Design (INF 350E) at UT Austin, which I took in Spring 2016. If you're curious, you can see initial study &lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/x8e0tjfkaqla6z9/Pinterest%20survey%20report.pdf?dl=0"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and the prototype review &lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/9zfs27y02i0igo1/Pinterest%20user%20test.pdf?dl=0"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. But bear in mind that this was no term paper nor final project, so the extent of user test results is more superficial.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>